If a king brings nothing but suffering to the people, get rid of him.
（アリババ）国民を
苦しめるだけの王なら　なくそう。
The people can choose their own representatives, set up a republic, and hold congress.
国民が　自分たちで代表を選び→
市民政府を作り　議会を開く。
The people themselves should be the ones who decide how their country should be.
国のあり方は
国民自身が決めるんだ。
Let's turn Balbadd into a People's Republic,
with no more disparity between the classes!
バルバッドを
格差のない共和制市民国家にする。
Let us carve a path with our own two hands and create a place where we can live in happiness!
全員の足で　踏み締めて
この地で生きていこう。
それが　新しいバルバッドの姿だ！
And that place is the new country of Balbadd!
（心の声）
≪もう俺は　ここから逃げないよ≫
I'm not going to run any longer.
≪お前との約束　ちょっと→
I'm going to have to put off our promise for a little bit though.
先延ばしになっちまうけどさ≫
≪待っててくれよ　アラジン≫
Wait for me, Aladdin.
♪♪～
Swing, pendulum.
（イスナーン）さあ　運命よ
大いに　逆流するがいい。
Reverse the flow of fate!
バルバッド～！
アリババ様～！
バルバッド　万歳！
アリババ様！
I'll never forget this sight.
≪今日の　この光景を忘れない≫
♪♪～
≪これが　ずっと続くように
目に　焼き付けておくんだ≫
I'll burn it into my mind so that things may be this way forever!
あっ。
♪♪～
Kassim's here.
来たな　カシム。
♪♪～
miwatasu kagiri no kouya ni hitori tatteirunda
In the wilderness, as far as the eye can see, stands a lone figure
sorya miburui mo surun darou
Surely he trembles as he stands
♪♪～
osanai shoujo ga yume ni miteiru hakuba no ouji mitaina mono
A young girl dreams of a prince on a white horse
♪♪～
bokura mo dokka de shiranai uchi ni kitai shiteshimatteitano kamo
Unwittingly, we also fall to such dreams of perfection
fukanzen na kono sekai wo dareka ga
No one will recreate
♪♪～
kakitashite kureru nante nai
this imperfect world for us
♪♪～
shinjiru toiu kotoba wo kimi ha kodomoppoi to warau kai?
Will you call me naïve if I say that I still dream?
miwatasu kagiri no kouya de yukisaki wo shimesu mono
In the wilderness, as far as the eye can see, shines a guiding light
♪♪～
mune ni daite aruitekou sekai ga hohoemu
Hold it close as you go and the world will smile upon you
kono basho ga doko darou to miagereba mabataku hoshi
If you're lost, consult the twinkling stars
♪♪～
sono shita de kimi wo omoeba warukunai yoru ni naru
If I think of you while gazing at those stars, the night brightens
tsumetai mune ni hi ga tomoru
and a warm fire lights in my heart
15th Night
Kassim's Answer
あっ…　カシムだ。
It's Kassim.
≫カシムだわ。
≪霧の団のカシムだ。
Kassim's here.
It's Kassim from the Fog Troupe.
Hey, you don't need to do this anymore.
なあ　殴り込む必要なんて
もうないぜ。→
この国には　王がいなくなった。→
This country no longer has a king.
Prince Alibaba said that the country belongs to the people!
国は　国民のものだと
アリババ王子が　おっしゃったんだ。
（イスナーン）さて
攻め込む理由がなくなったな。→
And so, you no longer have a reason to fight.
What will you do, Kassim?
どうする？　カシム。
≪ばんざ～い！
≫アリババ様！
よっ！　バルバッド！
ばんざ～い！
≪ばんざ～い！
≫アリババ様！
アリババ様～！
アリババ様　万歳！
（カシム）≪これ…　全部→
Alibaba, did you cause all this commotion?
お前がまとめたのか　アリババ≫
You've never failed to impress me.
≪まったく　お前はよぉ→
すごいヤツだよな。→
お前は　昔から　そうだった。→
Not even once.
誰かのためなら
正しいと思ったことをやり通す→
If you thought it was the right thing to do for
someone else's sake, you would never give up.
頑固な男だ。→
That's why I always stuck with you.
だからこそ　俺は　お前と→
ずっと　つるんでいたんだ。→
そして今　国のために…→
And now, for the sake of this country,
and for the sake of stopping my plans...
俺を止めるために→
お前の出した答えが
これなんだな≫
You've come up with this solution.
♪♪～
（カシム）≪けどよ…≫
But you know...
What's going to happen?
どうなるんだ？
なあ。
I dunno...
ふっ。　バルバッドは→
I heard that Balbadd has become a republic.
共和制になったと聞いた。→
これで
王のものであった国のすべては→
That what was once the king's country is now to be given equally to its people.
俺たち国民に
等しく分け与えられるわけだ。
（カシム）だが
それは　ごまかしではないのか？
What a load of crap.
（２人）ん？
（一同）えっ？
You said this country will be given to us.
（カシム）分け与えるだと？→
But isn't this entire country built upon our sweat and blood?
この国のすべては　俺たち国民の→
血と汗を流して築いた→
もともと
俺たちのものじゃないか！
Wasn't it ours to begin with?
それを　無能な政治で食い潰し→
Who destroyed this country through incompetent policies?
Who made us put up with a terrible government?
そのツケを
俺たちにかぶせたのは誰だ!?
（一同）あぁ…。
（カシム）覚えているだろう？→
You remember those days.
When heavy taxes took everything from us.
重税で　すべてが
むしり取られていく日々を。→
When starvation took our parents, our siblings.
飯も食えず死んでいった親　兄弟。
The dead won't ever come back!
死んだ者は　帰って来ないんだぞ！
くっ！
うぅ…。
んんっ！
If the monarchy disappears, do the
crimes of the monarchy disappear with it?
王政が消えれば　王族たちの罪も
消えるというのか!?
Of course not!
消えるはずはない！→
The monarchy is still an enemy we must defeat!
王族どもは　やはり
俺たちの倒すべき敵なんだ！
あっ！
そうだ…。
そうよ…→
That's right.
He's right.
共和制になっても
私の娘は　帰って来ないわ。
Even if we become a republic, my
daughter will never come back to me.
Neither will my baby sister.
俺の妹も…。
To talk about equality now is unfair.
なのに　今更
平等だなんて…　おかしい。
It doesn't make sense.
おかしい。
≪おかしい…。
≫おかしい…。
It doesn't make sense.
≫おかしい。
≪おかしい。
おかしい！
It doesn't make sense.
（３人）ああっ…。
さあ　今こそ　立ち上がるときだ！
Come! Now is the time we take a stand!
俺たちの国をむさぼってきた王族→
Now is the time we punish the royalty, the nobles, and the military who stole our country from us!
貴族　国軍どもを　処刑せよ!!
（一同）おお～～!!
（イスナーン）運命が　逆流しはじめた。→
Fate has begun to flow in reverse.
And I can finally reap the rewards of giving household vessels to you.
それでこそ　お前に　眷属器を
与えた甲斐があったというもの。
（一同）うおぉ～～!!
Oh no!
（バルカーク）そんな！
（シンドバッド）バカな！
No way!
Kassim, why?!
≪カシム…　なぜ!?≫
Sorry, Alibaba.
≪悪ぃな　アリババ≫
（カシム）これが　俺の答えだ。
This is my answer.
♪♪～
Aladdin!
（ジャーファル）アラジン　アラジン。
Is he... dead?
ねえ　この子
死んじゃったんじゃないの？
（ジャーファル）アラジン！　アラジン！
Aladdin!
（ウーゴ）アラジン→
Aladdin.
アラジン。
（アラジン）んん…。
Aladdin!
（ウーゴ）やあ。
あっ。
Hey.
Welcome back, Aladdin.
（ウーゴ）おかえり　アラジン。
ウーゴ…　くん？
Ugo!
そうだよ。
縦にしてくれるかい？　縦に。
That's right.
Do you think you could set me up straight?
（ウーゴ）彼らはね　俺が作ったんだ。→
I created these guys.
After you left, things got really quiet.
君がいなくなって　静かすぎてね。
I died, didn't I?
僕　死んじゃったんだね。
（ウーゴ）死んだ？
だって　体も　へんてこだし…。
Died?
I mean, look at how weird my body is!
ほらほら。
はははっ　大丈夫。
Look!
Don't worry, you haven't died.
君は　死んでいない。
自我を　ルフたちに
運んできてもらっただけだから。→
I just asked the rukh to bring your consciousness in here.
Your physical body is still alive on the surface.
肉体は　地上で生きているよ。
へえ～。
But it was close.
でも　危なかったんだよ。→
You were too reckless. You really could've died.
あんなむちゃをして　本当に
死んでしまうところだった。→
I tried to bring that other Magi too, but I wasn't able to.
あのマギも　ここに連れてこようと
しているんだけど→
ダメみたいだ。
♪♪～
（銀行屋）んん…。　ふん！
I will not allow those of the Holy Palace to do as they please.
（イスナーン）
聖宮のいいようにはさせん。
♪♪～
（イスナーン）まだまだ　これからだ→
Things are only getting started.
この世に　暗黒を作るのはな。
The world has only just started to become shrouded in darkness.
♪♪～
Kill them all!
皆殺しにしろ！
王宮の人間はもちろん→
Kill them all!
Kill everyone in the palace!
Kill all the nobles and powerful people in town!
街の貴族　豪族もだ！
（一同）おお～～！
♪♪～
We have a problem!
（モルジアナ）
大変です！　王宮の外へも→
Riots are spreading all around the palace!
ひどい争いが
広がりはじめています！
（一同）あっ！
（シンドバッド）くそ！→
Damn it! What is going on?
一体どうなっているんだ!?
There are people on the surface who are trying to reverse the flow of fate.
（ウーゴ）地上には　運命を
逆流させようとする者たちがいる。
運命を逆流させる？
Reverse the flow of fate?
本来　生命は　あるがまま→
Normally, life flows as you know it,
流れに生き
前へ前へと進んでいく。→
slowly but relentlessly forward.
You have been guided by the rukh,
君も　ルフに導かれるまま→
ジンや　その主と出会い
ここまで進んできた。
and on your journey here, you've
met various djinn and their masters.
それが運命。　だが→
That was all according to the flow of fate.
To take that forward progress and
regress it, to turn something into nothing,
そんな進化を退化に　有を無に→
to try to reverse the flow and turn
everything into yin or the negative.
すべてを陰なるものへ
逆流させようとする…→
That is known as falling into depravity.
それこそが　堕転だ。
堕転…。
Falling into depravity...
When that happens, the rukhs' bodies get dyed black.
（ウーゴ）そして　そのとき
ルフは　その身を黒く染める。→
As do Magi.
君たちマギも同じだ。→
黒く染められたマギが
君の前に　立ちはだかったのには→
I too was surprised when a Magi dyed in darkness appeared in front of you.
俺も驚いた。→
君は　あのとき
殺されるはずだったんだよ→
You should've died in that fight
彼らの作り出した
逆流する運命によって。→
as a result of the reversed fate his people created.
But I fought against that.
だが俺は　それに　あらがった。→
主が残してくれた魔力を
使いきってしまったけれどね。→
I used up all of the magoi left to me by my master though.
You tried to give me your magoi, but I'm not your djinn.
君は　魔力をくれようとしたけど→
俺は　君のジンじゃない。→
I cannot take your magoi, even if it is a copy of my master's.
だから　主の写し身たる君の力は
もう　もらえないんだ。
もう　君を守ってあげられない。
I can no longer protect you.
あっ…。
だから→
That's why I've used the very last dredges of power left in the flute to call you here.
笛に残った　本当に最後の力で→
君を　ここに呼んだんだ。
君に　大切なものを渡すために。
There is something very important I must give you.
ん？
ご覧。
Look.
♪♪～
アリババくん！
Alibaba!
The way things are now, your chosen king will perish.
（ウーゴ）君の選んだ王が
このままでは滅びる。
But this is not how fate was supposed to flow.
しかし
これは　本来の流れではない。
暗黒を作り出す　運命の逆流。
あっ！
It is a reverse flow, brought about to create darkness.
人々が　力を尽くしても
もはや及ばず→
Even if the people try their hardest to
repel the darkness, it will not be enough.
When the world turns to darkness,
世界が　黒く転じるとき→
the people need the power to cut away and cut across the darkness.
この世には　闇を切り裂き→
打ち晴らす力が　必要なんだ。
In other words, a miracle.
（ウーゴ）そう…　奇跡が。
It's a Magi's mission to carry that out.
それこそが　マギの使命。→
In order for you to fulfill your mission, you must first go to a certain place.
その使命を果たすため　君は
ある場所に行かなくてはならない。
（ウーゴ）世界を　運命を→
So that you may learn firsthand about this world, about the flow of fate.
君自身を知るために。
When you have, you will gain my master's wisdom.
そして　これが終われば　君は→
手に入れているよ。　我が主…→
The wisdom of Solomon.
ソロモンの知恵を。
Goodbye, Aladdin.
≪さようなら　アラジン。→
I will never see you again.
二度と　君に会えない≫
Let's be friends!
（回想）((友達になってよ))
あっ…。
≪まだ　君を一人にするのは→
It might be too soon to leave you to your own devices though.
早いかもしれないけど…≫
≪いや　もう違う。→
No, that's not true.
Aladdin was able to make so many friends on the surface.
アラジンは　外で仲間を　友達を→
あんなに
作れるようになったんだ。→
本当は
もう　俺がいなくても　大丈夫≫
Even without me by his side, Aladdin will be just fine.
開け　ゴマ！
Open... sesame!
♪♪～
≪聖宮よ
その偉大なる王ソロモンよ→
O Royal Palace! O mighty King Solomon!
この子を　再び地上に。→
Please return this child to the surface.
And please bestow upon him your
knowledge, your power of miracles!
そして　あなたの知恵を　奇跡を→
どうか　この子に！≫
ここは…　どこ？
Where am I?
あっ。
This is the entrance to a great maelstrom of knowledge.
（ソロモン王の声）ここは
莫大な知識の渦への入り口。→
Look.
ご覧。　あのひと粒ひと粒が→
Each little speck is a particle of the world's truths.
世界の真実の素粒子たち。→
今からお前は　そのすべてを巡り→
You will now travel amongst them all and be reborn anew, Magi.
生まれ変わるのだ　マギよ。
君は　誰なの？
Who are you?
All will be clear once you complete this long journey.
（ソロモン王の声）すべてが分かる…
この長い旅を終えれば。
Thank goodness. Color has returned to his cheeks.
（ジャーファル）
よかった　顔に赤みが戻ってきた。
ああ…。
≫うおぉ～！
≫王族を殺せ～！
≫娘を返して！
Kill the royalty!
Give my daughter back!
（ジャーファル）うん。
（ジャーファル）あとは頼みます。
私たちは行かなくては。→
Please take good care of him. We must be going.
Let's head to the palace, Masrur.
王宮へ向かうぞ　マスルール。
んん…　くっ！
でやっ！
ふん！
ぐわっ…。
でやぁ～！
うわっ！
（バルカーク）
副王様　国軍総攻撃のご命令を！
Deputy King!
Order the armed forces to go on the offensive!
（サブマド）あっ…。
相手は　市民とはいえ→
They may be our citizens, but this is an all-out war.
これは　もはや戦争。
広場も街も　死傷者だらけです。
The number of casualties in town and the plaza are growing.
（バルカーク）どうか　ご決断を。
（サブマド）あぁ…。→
Please give your order!
どうしよう？　アリババ…。
What should we do, Alibaba?
国軍は　半数で正門へ向かい→
Half of the military will head towards the main gates.
See if they can stop the rebels from entering.
反乱民の侵入を
食い止めてくれないか？
残りは　すでに侵入した者たちの
制圧に当たってくれ。
The rest of the army is to try to gain control over the rebels that have already broken through.
My brothers and those injured should take refuge in the inner sanctuary.
負傷者と兄さんたちは
本殿へ避難を。
As the former head of the enemy forces, I will take the lead.
敵の頭領のもとへは　俺が行く。
I will stop Kassim!
カシムは　俺が止める。
≪わあ～！
≫うおぉ～！
（ザイナブ）国軍どももたあいないね。
（ハッサン）このまま→
We cut through the military like butter.
Let's keep up the pace and break through to the inner sanctuary.
本殿まで突き進もうぜ。
（一同）ん？
（カシム）来た。
He's here.
（ザイナブ）ううっ！
（ハッサン）おっ…。
♪♪～
ふん！　よう　アリババ。
Yo, Alibaba.
どうした？
おっかねぇ顔してよぉ。
What's the matter?
That's one scary face you've got.
Kassim, what are you planning?
カシム　どういうつもりだ？
王政は　もう終わったんだ。
The monarchy is done for.
もう血を流す必要は
どこにもないのに。
There's no reason for all this bloodshed!
それなのに　お前は　なぜ！
Why are you doing this?
Answer me, Kassim!
答えろ　カシム！
お前こそ　どういうつもりなんだ？
アリババ。→
I could ask you the same thing, Alibaba.
平等？　王のいない国？
Equality? A country without a king?
When did I ever wish for something like that?
そんなもの
いつ　俺が求めたってんだ!?
くっ！
Damn it, Kassim!
カシム　てめぇ！
≪あいつらも　黒縛霧刀か≫
They also have swords of shackling ebon fog?
≪でも　霧なんか
このアモンの炎で→
Doesn't matter. Amon's flames...
will cut right through their fog!
蹴散らしてやるぜ！≫
（ザイナブ）赤幻霧刀！
Sword of phantasmal scarlet fog!
≪くっ！　し…　視界が…≫
My vision!
♪♪～
Say, Alibaba.
（カシム）なあ　アリババよ→
お前は　王族の子は王族として
生きるべきだと思うか？
Do you think that a royal's kid should live as royalty?
くっ！
（カシム）スラムのガキは→
And that a kid from the slums should always live as a slum's brat?
一生
スラムで生きるべきだと思うか？
♪♪～
ううっ！
（カシム）俺は　そうは思わねぇ。→
I don't.
We're all humans.
誰もが　同じ人間だ。
♪♪～
だから　誰にでも→
Which means that any one of us is qualified to become king!
王になる資格が　あるはずだ。
はっ…。
でやぁ～！
Amon!
アモン！
♪♪～
なっ！
（ハッサン）なんだ!?　あの剣は。
What's that?
Look at his sword!
カシム…　つまり　お前は→
In other words, Kassim, you wanted to become king. Isn't that right?
自分が王になりたかっただけだって
言うんだな？
さあな。
Who knows.
じゃあ　なんだってんだ!?
これだけ周りを巻き込んどいて！
Then what?!
Why have you involved so many people in this?
これ以上
好きなようには　させねぇ！
I won't let you do as you please!
Shut up already!
ごちゃごちゃ　うるせぇ！
黄侵霧刀で溶かしてやるぜ～！→
I'll melt your mouth of with my sword of corroding golden fog!
Take this!
てりゃ～！
ふん！
What!
なんだと!?
（一同）くっ！
ふん！
ううっ…。
ううっ！　くっ…。　あっ！
Call back your troops, Kassim.
兵を退け。　カシム→
力ずくでも　お前を退かせる。
Or I'll make you do it by force.
♪♪～
I won't back down, Alibaba.
アリババ　俺は退かないぜ。→
I'd rather die than back down here.
このまま退くくらいなら
死んだ方が　ましだ。
（カシム）てめぇも　そのくらいの覚悟で
俺を　迎え撃ったんだろうが。
You came here determined to do the same, didn't you?
So let's fight.
だから　殺れよ。
うっ…。
（カシム）殺れ。
To the death.
くっ！
（カシム）殺れ。
To the death.
♪♪～
殺れっつってんだろ　アリババ～!!
Fight to the death, Alibaba!
カシム…　てめぇ！
Damn you, Kassim!
Please strike, Prince Alibaba!
（バルカーク）
お討ちください　アリババ様！→
One strike and all will end!
これで　すべてが終わります！
♪♪～
くっ！　くっそ～～!!
Damn it!!
♪♪～
できるか…　バカ野郎！
As if I could do that, you idiot!
If you withdraw your troops now Kassim, the revolt will stop!
カシム　今すぐ
兵を退けば　暴動は止まる！
そしたら　お前らの処遇だって
まだ　どうなるか分からない。
If that happens, there'll still be a chance for you too!
So please!
だから！
ははっ。
ほんとに甘ぇな　お前はよ。→
You're too soft, Alibaba.
んな甘いわけねぇだろ。
I'm nowhere near as naïve as you are.
（カシム）じゃあな。
あぁ…。
See ya.
（２人）くっ！
（ザイナブ）うっ！
んん…。
≪やるしかねぇな≫
I guess I have no choice.
（イスナーン）((運命を呪うならば→
If you want to curse your own fate, use the power that sleeps within this weapon.
武器に宿る
本来の力を使うがいい))
But in the case that you are not the right container for that power, you will die.
（イスナーン）((君が
それを使う器でない場合は→
命を落とすことになるがな))
Curse my fate, huh?
運命か…。
ふん！
はっ！
（３人）ああっ…。
（シンドバッド）なっ！
（カシム）うぅ…。
（カシム）んんっ！　ぐっ…。→
見ていろ…　スラムの野郎ども→
Take a good look, people of the slums!
国軍　貴族　王族ども…。→
Military, nobles, and royalty too!
I'll show you proof that anyone can be a container for power!
どんなヤツにでも
力が宿りうることを→
証明してやるぜ。
集え！　すべて　俺のもとに！
Come to me now!
♪♪～
（ザイナブ）あっ…　ああっ！
（ハッサン）あっ！
ああっ。
♪♪～
If a person like him uses his blood to command the household vessels,
（イスナーン）やはり
ヤツほどの血をもって命ずれば→
眷属たちは　一つに集う。→
the vessels will all gather as one.
He has become the bearer of the ebon container.
黒き器の持ち主よ。
（カシム）うっ！　うぅ…。
あぁ…。
（カシム）うっ！→
うぅ…　んんっ！　ぐぐっ…。→
ぐおぉ～…　んん…。
♪♪～
（一同）ああっ…。
No way!
バカな！　まさか　あれは…。
It can't be!
グオォ～～!!
あぁ…。
黒い…　魔人…。
A... black... demon!
ああっ！
（イスナーン）くはっ！
♪♪～
グオォ～～!!
（一同）うわっ！
あっ…　あぁ…。
♪♪～
"kimi ni ha yuuki ga aru"
"You're a hero."
sono hitokoto wo shinji tobidashita
Off you went, believing in those words
mawari ha kare wo waratte
While those around you mocked you
♪♪～
"douse nani hitotsu aitsu ni ha dekinai sa"
"Let him go. He can't do anything."
iwaseteoke
Let them talk
kimi ha keshite yowaku nanka nai
You're far from weak
dare ni mo hatasenakatta yume wo negae tsuyoku
Believe in those dreams no one else could reach!
♪♪～
dare ni mo hatasenakatta yume wo negae tsuyoku
Believe in those dreams no one else could reach!
kanarazu kanaete miserutte
You'll definitely make them come true
♪♪～
saa mizukara no hata kakage
Come, fly your own flag
susume mae ni
and keep moving forward
nijimu namida ha
The tears you shed
kimi no akashi
are proof that you're alive
♪♪～
chikara ni narou
Draw strength from your tears!
mayou toki ha kono boku ga soba ni iru
When you are in trouble, I will be by your side
dakara ikou
So go!
♪♪～
sekai no subete wo mi ni
And see the world
You're the only one who can save this country!
I'll make you mine!
Why would you go so far, Alibaba?
Next time: Solomon's Wisdom
16th Night
Solomon's Wisdom
As long as I still draw breath, I will fight!
（シンドバッド）
この国を救えるのは君だけだ！
（ジュダル）
お前は　俺のものにしてやるよ！
なぜ　君は　そこまでするんだい？
アリババくん。
俺は戦う　生きてるかぎり。
初めに、アルジェリアでの人質事
件です。
日本人の死亡や生存未確認の情報
が
アルジェリア政府から提供された
ことを受けて
日本政府は、社員らが巻き込まれ
た